A Guide to the Han Schroeder Architectural Collection, 1914-1992
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Han Schroeder Architectural Collection, 1914-1992
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-064
40.0 cu. ft. 12 boxes; 5 map cases
The materials in the collection consist of correspondence, clippings, publications, teaching materials, scrapbooks, photographs, family information and architectural materials relating to Han Schroeder's career.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated in January 1989 by Han Schroeder to the International Archive of Women in Architecture housed in the Special Collections Department of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Libraries. An addition to the collection was made in 1992, after Schroeder's death. Materials dated after 1992 were placed in the collection by Laura Katz Smith, Curator of Manuscripts.
Alternate Form Available
...
Biographical/Historical Note
Han Schroeder was born in July 16, 1918 in Utrecht, Netherlands. Her artistic and architectural education began early, when her mother commissioned the architect Gerrit Thomas Rietveld to design what is now known as the Rietveld-Schroeder House, completed in 1924. For this house Rietveld employed the revolutionary concept of moveable walls to make the interior flexible, thereby redefining the limits of space. Growing up in this house fueled Han's interest in architecture, and was the beginning of her friendship to Rietveld and her devotion to his ideas. With the encouragement of her family, Han developed her artistic talent, and worked with Rietveld and G. van de Groenekan on carpentry and furniture making in her teenage years. In 1936 she entered the Federal Institute of Technology in Zurich, Switzerland, and graduated in 1940 with the degree of Diplom Architekt. She did not return to the Netherlands during World War II, but worked in Portugal (where she worked for the Red Cross and the Netherlands Embassy) and Great Britain. She returned to the Netherlands in 1946. From 1946 to 1949 she worked in the Municipal Museum of Modern Art in Amsterdam under W. Sandberg. Beginning in 1949 Schroeder worked first as a draftsman and then as a personal assistant to Rietveld. During these years she experimented with materials and concepts of interior design. She worked with Rietveld on Federal housing projects, schools, exhibitions, and the Sonsbeek Sculpture Pavillion, among other projects. She opened her own office in 1954. At that time she was one of two registered woman architects among 3000 registered men in the Netherlands. The most significant designs she did between 1954 and 1963 were the Gaastra House in Zeist; Ellinchem, a Center for Rejected and Problem Children in Ellecom; the Academy of Social Work, Amsterdam, where she designed a snack bar and auditorium; the Kessler House, a recreation building for employees of the Netherlands Steel Furnaces; and various Youth and Community Centers in Utrecht, Oldebrock, and Eerbeek. During this time she also designed stationery and exhibits. In 1963 she emigrated to the United States. She first worked at firms in Los Angeles, California, but accepted a position at Adelphi University in Garden City, New York, to teach interior design. In 1966 she taught at the Parsons School of Design in New York City, and then at the New York Institute of Technology from 1967 to 1979. In 1979 she became a Professor of Interior Design at Virginia Commonwealth University in Richmond, Virginia. She retired in 1988, and died in Amsterdam on March 20, 1992.
text
Scope and Content
The materials in the collection consist of correspondence, clippings, publications, teaching materials, scrapbooks, photographs, family information and architectural materials. Architectural materials include drawings, photographs, specifications, and reports. The materials are arranged in chronological order except where otherwise noted. All project materials are grouped together.
The collection also contains materials about the Rietveld-Schroeder House and biographical material about Rietveld and her mother, Tr. Schroeder-Schraeder, examples and other materials associated with her typographical (or stationery design) work, and work-related and personal photographs.
Arrangement
...
The following five books were removed from the collection and placed in the Rare Book Collection:
Haags Gemeentemuseum Piet Mondriaan
Dutch Architecture: 1907-1917 by Theodore M. Brown
Vormen Van De Kleur
Villa's en Buitenhuizen by Jan Henselmans
Theo van Doesburg Propagandist and Practitioner of the Avant-Garde 1909-1923 by Hannah L. Hedrick
Index Terms
Subjects:
Architects--Virginia; Architectural drawing--20th century; Architecture; Architecture--Study and teaching; Interior design; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Occupations:
Architects
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings
Contents List
- Personal Papers,1925-1992
  - General files,1925-1992
    - Address Book,1954-1962 (Box-folder 9:35)
    - Announcement of Her Death and Obituary,1992 (Box-folder 9:23)
    - Architectural certificates (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Architecture Diploma,1940 (Oversize Map-Case 1/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
    - Astrological work of Schroeder (Box-folder 10:15)
    - Biographical Information (Box-folder 10:5)
    - Cab Calloway, autographed image of (Box-folder 11:19)
    - Certificate of Architectural Registration,1990 (Box-folder 9:41)
    - Class Notes, School of Social Work,1962 (Box-folder 3:31)
    - Computer Handwriting Analysis of Schroeder (Box-folder 10:24)
    - Education Documents,1940 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Fondue/cocktail recipes (Box-folder 5:31)
    - Garbo Poster (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 5)
    - Insurance Policies,1959-1963 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - International Documents (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Items mounted near her desk at time of her death (Box 9:29)
    - Legal Papers,1958-1959 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Manuscript and Typescript Writings (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Obituary appearing in Richmond Times-Dispatch,April 2, 1992 (Box-folder 9:25)
    - Pamphlet Titled, You and The Atomic Bomb (Box-folder 11:12)
    - Photo I.D. From Allied Board of Trade,1960 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Project 2050 Donation Letters - financial donation to VCU,1986 (Box-folder 9:16)
    - Project 2050, Goals,1980 (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Reminders of things to be done,1992 (Box-folder 9:24)
    - Report Cards; Early photographs and letters, 1925-1933 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Rulers (Box-folder 7:3)
    - School work; photographs; negatives; sketchbook,1930-1939 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Schroeder, M. ( Sister of Han)(Amsterdam, The Netherlands),1954 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - Transcripts and other Evidence of Education/ Employment (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence Files A-N (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Correspondence Files O-Z (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 10:6, Box-folder 10:4, Box-folder 1:5-6)
    - BNA Correspondence and Documents (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Cards from Schroeder to Florence Maly (Box-folder 10:20)
    - Misc. Postcards and Letters sent to Schroeder (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Photographs,1953, 1975-1981, and undated
    - Early Years, photographs (Box-folder 8:28)
    - Family photos and miscellaneous photos (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Florence Maly, photographs (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Greeting Book For Florence Moly By Schroeder,1953 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Kockengen, photographs (Box-folder 8:27)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, taken by Schroeder (Box 10:21)
    - Negatives (Box 8)
    - Photographs and Correspondence with Friends (Box-folder 10:23)
    - Photographs of her mother/Article from Scrapbook (Box-folder 10:22)
    - Photographs left on her desk (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Postcards, Travel photos (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Schroeder and Acquaintances, photographs, (2 folders) (Box-folder 10:25-26)
    - Schroeder Condo in Richmond, slides (Box-folder 9:30)
    - Schroeder and her Mother, slides,1975-1981 (Box-folder 8:24)
    - Schroeder Photo I.D.'s (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Sketches,1989 and undated
    - Drawings/Sketches (Box-folder 1:8-9)
    - Floor Plan for Schroeder/Maly Condo (Box-folder 10:7)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings and Correspondence (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Pencil drawings of city scenes,1938 and undated (Oversize Map-Case 1/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
    - Schroeder's last architectural Drawing -- Repair of her condo, 1989 (Box-folder 9:21)
- Professional Papers,1920-1992
  - General Files,1953-1967
    - Agreement with Successor to Projects,1963 (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Congress of the International Federation of Interior Designers,1967 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Federation Of Interior Design and Applies Arts -- Council for Architecture (Box-folder 4:23)
    - Flyers About An Exhibition at Virginia Tech of her work (Box 9:27)
    - Kindertehuizen booklet [Childrens homes],1953 (Box 1:36)
    - Kurt Schwitters Catalogue with Designs By Schroeder,1956 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Impressions of the Work of Personnel Consultants in the U.S.,1961 (Box-folder 4:24)
    - Materials and Building Codes,1962 (Box-folder 3:30)
    - Personnel,1961-1963 (Box-folder 3:29)
    - Scrapbook (Box-folder 6:21)
    - Video of an Interview discussing IAWA and Schroeder (Box-folder 9:28)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings (Box-folder 6:12-14)
    - Interviews and Publications about her work (Box-folder 9:37)
    - Publications (Box-folder 6:15-18)
  - Correspondence,1962-1992
    - Correspondence,1963-1984 (Box-folder 5:17, Box-folder 10:10)
    - John A Emmi, Correspondence, 1981, 1992 (Box-folder 9:9, Box-folder 9:22)
    - Mies Van Der Rohe, Correspondence,1964 (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York City) -- Correspondence,1962 (Box-folder 8:14, Box-folder 5:1)
    - Sandberg of Municipal Museum (Box-folder 1:35)
    - Sigfried Giedion, Correspondence (Box-folder 11:20)
  - Drawings/Sketches, 1953-1958
    - Chair Design (Box-folder 5:27)
    - Examples of Her Work,1955-1958 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Furniture Design, 1955 (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Heymans (Amsterdam, The Netherlands), sketches (Box 5:30)
    - R. Nieuekerke, living room, Utrecht, sketches,1953 (Box-folder 1:38)
    - Sketches (Box-folder 6:20)
    - Window Details (Box-folder 6:19)
    - Window and Door Detail Drawings,1954 (Box-folder 1:39)
  - Gerrit Rietveld
    - Articles About Rietveld Furniture Design (Box-folder 11:22)
    - Lecture about Rietveld (Box-folder 5:32)
    - Letter From G. Rietveld (Box-folder 11:21)
    - Letter From Schroeder Commenting on a Rietveld Furniture Catalogue (Box-folder 9:20)
    - Other Rietveld Designs -- Specifications for "Hoograven" (Utrecht, The Netherlands) (Box-folder 5:34)
    - Ottagono, Issue 26, includes article on Gerrit Rietveld (Box-folder 8:22)
    - Publications About Rietveld (2 folders) (Box-folder 12:1-2)
    - Rietveld Architecture, slides (Doubles) (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Rietveld Furniture, slides (2 folders) (Box-folder 12:4-5)
    - Rietveld-Schroeder House -- Gerrit Rietveld (Box-folder 5:33)
    - Rietveld Writings (2 folders) (Box-folder 11:13-14)
  - Graphic Design
    - Central Museum Utrecht (Box-folder 11:17)
    - Graphic Work (Box-folder 9:31, Box-folder 11:11, Box-folder 9:39-40)
  - Photographs
    - Negatives of Project Photographs (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Oversize Project Photographs (Oversize Map-Case 1/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
    - Portfolio of Schroeder's Work (3 folders) (Box-folder 10:17-19)
    - Project Photographs (Box-folder 7:1, Box-folder 8:26)
    - Slides of Schroeder's Work (Box-folder 9:33)
  - Reference Files,1920-1982
    - Architecture Drawings, John F. Kennedy High School -- Barstow, California, 1967 (Box-folder 10:2)
    - De Stijl
      - Publications, about De Stijl,1987, 1990 (Box-folder 11:25)
      - Exhibit, "De Stijl, Visions of Utopia"
      - Doctoral thesis, Corrie Nagtegall entitled " De Stijl von I.K. Bonset" (Box-folder 9:18)
      - Slides, De Stijl Exhibit,1982 (Box-folder 9:12)
      - Book, "De Stijl De Stijl,"1951 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Publications, The Future of Architecture,1980 (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Publications, The Future of Design,1982 (Box-folder 10:16)
    - Slides, Dr. Horrenstein's House,1926 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Slides, G.Z.C. Jewelry Store,1920 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Slides, Sousbeek Sculpture Pavillion,1954-1955 (Box 8:6)
    - Thesis, about Jean Prouve,1981 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Rietveld Schroeder House
    - Architectural Drawing, Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Articles, about Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 11:16)
    - Articles, written about Schroeder or Rietveld Schroeder House (2 folders) (Box-folder 11:5-6)
    - Audiocassettes, (1)Congress: Design 1987 Amsterdam, Bertus Mulder The Rietveld/Schroder House (2) Unclear title dated November 9, 1990 (Box-folder 9:17)
    - Audiocassettes, Rietveldlezing I and II [Rietveld Lecture] (Box-folder 9:19)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Rietveld Schroeder house (Box-folder 11:18)
    - Interior/Exterior Specifications, Book, Rietveld Schroeder House (Utrecht, The Netherlands) (Box-folder 5:36)
    - Lecture Notes (Box-folder 11:23)
    - Paper Model, Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 9:13)
    - Plans, Contracts, Deeds, Correspondence, Rietveld Schroeder House (Utrecht, The Netherlands) (Box-folder 5:35)
    - Postcard, Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Publications, about Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 11:24)
    - Rietveld's Design for the Schroeder House, 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - Rietveld's Design for the Schroeder House, 3 (Box 7)
    - Rietveld Schroeder House -- Tr. Schroeder -Schrader: Bewoonster Van Het Rietveld Schroederhuis (Box-folder 5:40)
    - Reitveld Schroeder House (Prins Hendriklaan 50, 3583 EP Utrecht, Netherlands; 1924; House)1924 (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 1, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 2)
    - Sale Contract/ Deed of Rietveld Schroeder House (Box-folder 8:23)
    - Slides, Rietveld Schroeder House (2 folders) (Box-folder 12:6-7)
    - Slides, Rietveld Schroeder House Models (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Stichting Rietveld Schroeder Huis (Utrecht, The Netherlands) -- Meetings (Box-folder 5:37)
    - Stichting Rietveld Schroeder Huis (Utrecht, The Netherlands) -- Meeting Minutes (Box-folder 5:38)
    - Stichting Rietveld Schroeder Huis (Utrecht, The Netherlands) -- Plans For Restoring the Interior (Box-folder 5:39)
  - Typography
    - Typography -- Stationary Design (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Typography -- Samples (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Typography -- Designs for Writing Paper (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Typography -- Designs for Calling Cards (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Typography -- Cliché Drawings for publications (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Typography -- Designs for Christmas Cards (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Typography -- Schrale Beton (Box-folder 6:7)
    - Typography -- Hollandsche Beton My (Contracting Firm) -- Stationary Design (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Typography -- De Letter Op Straat (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Typography -- Kinder Hulp (Box-folder 6:10-11)
- Faculty Papers
  - General Files,1963-1990
    - Articles, Lectures, and administrative memoranda, 1986 (Box-folder 10:14)
    - Autobiographical Essay and Curriculum Vitae,1980 (Box-folder 5:25)
    - Correspondence,1963-1990 (Box-folder 10:12)
    - Correspondence with University of Illinois,1969 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Curriculum and Department Discussion (Box-folder 8:25)
    - MIT Exhibition, "Form and Use in Architecture,"1969 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - Parsons School of Design, 1971 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Product Engineering,1971 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Promotions and Salary Information,1981 (Box-folder 10:13)
    - "A Red Balloon" -- Thoughts about my classes,1968 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Studies For a Small Art Department. Adelphi University (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Lectures,1986-1987
    - Audiocassette 1, Artistic Trends of the 1920s,1986 (Box 7)
    - Lecture Notes,1987 (Box-folder 5:26)
    - Videotape 1 (Betamax), Lecture, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Videotape 2 (Betamax), Lecture at Virginia Tech, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Videotape 3 (Betamax), Lecture (Box 7)
  - Letters from Students,1980-1982, and undated
    - Correspondence with Students,1980-1982, and undated (Box-folder 9:32, Box-folder 10:11, Box-folder 11:15)
    - Easter Letter from JoAnn Perciavalle (a former student),1980 (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Letter from Deborah Finnerty (a former student),1980 (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Letter from Sharon (a former student) (Box 9:8)
  - New York Institute of Technology
    - General Information from NYI Tech. (Box-folder 9:38)
    - New York Tech various course outlines, Class List, Exams (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Thesis Proposals and Literature from Parsons/ NY Tech [her students and course materials] (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Student Work
    - Slides, Student Work (Box-folder 9:36)
    - Student Thesis (Box-folder 8:21)
    - Student Work (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU)
    - Autobiographical Information, submitted for tenure review VCU (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Design Assignments at VCU (Box-folder 9:34)
    - Furniture Design (I+II) Coursework at VCU (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Introduction of Architecture Coursework at VCU (2 folders) (Box-folder 11:3-4)
    - Letter from Dianne Tupper regarding Schroeder's original tenure at VCU rejection (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Letters of Resignation and Correspondence (Box-folder 9:15)
    - Paper Presented at VCU Seminar -- What is the Future for the Field of Interior Design and the Designer (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Tenure Documents for VCU (Box-folder 9:6)
- Project Records, 1914-1975
  - Project 1. Vrijgezel (Unknown Location; No Date; House Boat) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 2. Mej. Julsinga ( Barendzstraat 9, Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date; renovation ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 3. Family Van Daalen ( Bergeyk, The Netherlands; No Date; Playroom) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 4. Dr. Ris Ermelo (Unknown Location; No Date; Sitting Room) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 5. Mrs. F. Maly ( Rockville Centre, New York, USA; 1954; Cabinetry) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 6. Mevr. Schorer ( Unknown Location; Unknown Date; Bookshelf ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10, Box-folder 1:13)
  - Project 7. "Rugleuning divanbed Meubeltent. Byenkorf" G. Rietveld ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date; Furniture ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 10)
  - Project 8. "3 persoons bank", G. Rietveld ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date; Furniture ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9)
  - Project 9. "Kratleuningstoel" Crate Arm-Chair, G. Rietveld ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date; Furniture ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9)
  - Project 10. "Bijzettafeltje" End Table, G. Rietveld ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; No Date; Furniture ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9)
  - Project 11. Bredero Beton, G. Rietveld ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date; Stand ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9)
  - Project 12. "Plan tot splitsen van het perceel" Plan to split the plot (Jan van Scorelstraat, Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1914; [Renovation] ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9)
  - Project 13. De Vonk ( Noodwykerhout, The Netherlands; 1937; Cabinetry ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 9, Box-folder 1:14)
  - ** Project 14. Rademacher Schorer ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; No Date ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 8)
  - Project 15. Mr. Moltzer ( Amersfoort, The Netherlands; 1950; Kitchen ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 8, Box 1:15)
  - Project 16. Tr. Schroeder ( Prins Hendriklaan, Schildersbuurt, Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1950 ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 7)
  - Project 17. H. Heydenrijk Inc ( New York, USA; 1952; Office/ Showroom ) (Oversize Map-Case 1/Drawer 1/Folder 7, Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1/Drawer 2/Folder 10, Box-folder 1:16)
  - Project 18. Mevrouw L. Cremer ( Kramer, Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1953; House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 7, Box-folder 7:2, Box 1:17)
  - Project 19. Edith Vermeer ( Unknown Location; 1953 ) (Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 7, Box-folder 1:18)
  - Project 20. Heer en Mevrouw W. can Norden ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1953; Changing room ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6, Box-folder 1:19)
  - Project 21. Heer Blom ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1954 ) (Box-folder 1:20, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6)
  - Project 22. Family De Mol van Otterloo ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1954; [Renovation] ) (Box-folder 1:21, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6)
  - Project 23. "Werkende vrouw" Working Woman ( Unknown Location; 1954; House Boat ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6)
  - Project 24. Family Thiadens ( Koningslaan, Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1954; Interior ) (Box-folder 1:22, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6)
  - Project 25. "Kinderhulp" ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1954-1955 ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 6)
  - Project 26. "Kinderhuis De Poort" Childrens gate (Meerweg 49, Bussum, The Netherlands; 1955-1956; Pre-School/ Day Care ) (Box-folder 1:23-24, Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 5, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 4)
  - Project 27. Heer W.A. Eykema Overweg ( Beethovenweg, Noordwyk, The Netherlands; 1955-1956; House ) (Box-folder 1:25, Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 1 / Folder 3)
  - Project 28. "School voor Maatschappelyk Werk" School for Social Work ( Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1955-1957; School ) (Box-folder 1:26-29, Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 9, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 8, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 7)
  - Project 29. H. Salet ( Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1955-1962; House ) (Box-folder 1:30, Box-folder 7:2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 6)
  - Project 30. Mevr. Van der Kraan ( Rubenslaan 14, Bilthoven, The Netherlands; 1956; Livingroom Renovation ) (Box-folder 5:29, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 5)
  - Project 31. "Landgoed Wielbergen" ( Angerlo, The Netherlands; 1956; House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 5, Box-folder 1:31, Box-folder 7:2)
  - Project 32. Fam. Beuke ( Ellecom, The Netherlands; 1956; House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 4, Box-folder 7:2)
  - Project 33. Clubhuis West ( West Utrecht, The Netherlands; 1956-1960; Club House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 4, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 3, Box-folder 2:1-4, Box-folder 7:2)
  - Project 34. Mr. M. G. Rood ( Lomanstraat 18, Amsterdam, The Netherlands; 1956-1962; House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 2, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 1, Box-folder 1:32)
  - Project 35. "Kindertehuis Ellinchem" ( Zutphensestraatweg 38, Ellecom, The Netherlands; 1955-1963; Orphanage ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 2 / Folder 1, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 3 / Folder 10, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 3 / Folder 9, Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 3 / Folder 8, Box-folder 2:5-20, Box-folder 7:2)
  - Project 36. Heer Dr. W. Lammers ( Julianalaan 229, Bilthoven, The Netherlands; 1957; House ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 3 / Folder 7)
  - Project 37. N. V. Ripolin ( [Voorstraat 18, Utrecht], The Netherland; 1957; Fair Stand ) (Oversize Map-Case 1 / Drawer 3 / Folder 7, Box-folder 1:33, Box-folder 7:2)